Chris Woodley

Front-end Developer

141 Joyce Avenue Harrison, Ohio 45030 (626) 975-0740 chriswoodley@me.com cwoodley.com

Professional Summary

Experienced Front-End Developer with a focus on building engaging user interfaces for Software as a Service applications. Proficient with JavaScript, modern JavaScript frameworks, and testing methodologies. Strong track record in remote team leadership, building design systems, and ensuring code quality standards. Committed to team growth and collaboration.

Experience

Lead Front-End Software Engineer (April 2022 - October 2023)

Losant, Cincinnati, Ohio

- Worked remotely with Developers and Engineering Managers to deliver best implementation of features for the Internet of Things (IoT) platform using React and Redux.
- Developed a Design System with React, Storybook and Styled Components used to unify the User Interface of the IoT platform.
- Spearheaded code reviews and promoted software testing best practices using Jest and the React Testing Library.
- Guided team members by providing team and engineering updates and supported them in their career growth.

Senior Front-End Software Engineer (September 2020 – March 2022)

Losant, Cincinnati, Ohio

- Followed business requirements to deliver software features that enabled customers to build IoT workflows that are meaningful to their application using JavaScript and React.
- Resolved User Interface defects and wrote front-end unit tests with Jest and the React Testing Library.
- Performed code reviews to ensure quality and style standards set by the development team were met.

Senior Front-End Software Engineer (December 2018 - August 2020)

Genetesis, Mason, Ohio

- Wrote efficient, reliable, and scalable code to create the Site Reader application which helped doctors view and determine the prognosis of Magnetocardiograph (MCG) scans conducted on patients experiencing chest pain.
- Followed business requirements to create the Operator application that supported the operation of the CardioFlux MCG medical device using the Electron framework.
- Utilized the Vue.js JavaScript framework, Storybook.js and SCSS to create a Shared UI library containing re-usable components, directives, mixins, filters, utility functions, and SCSS mixins.
- Created a NodeJS back-end PDF service to dynamically generate PDF documents using Puppeteer.
- Wrote Front-end Unit Tests for Vue.js components and Vuex Store Modules using Jest.

Senior Consultant - Front-End Software Engineer (April 2018 - December 2018)

Sogeti, Cincinnati, Ohio

- Produced code to create a Revenue Cycle Asset Management Software used internally by GE Aviation. The software helps GE Aviation customers in making informed decisions on commercial aircraft part maintenance and replacement.
- Utilized the Vue.js JavaScript framework, Storybook.js, and Rollup.js to create modern UI components.
- Implemented software features using modern UI components within a Micro Front-end architecture.
- Wrote UI component Unit Tests using Jest.

Front-End Software Engineer (December 2016 - March 2018)

Shared Services, Cincinnati, Ohio

- Authored high-quality code to create a Revenue Cycle Management software that replaced GE Centricity software used by medical practices.
- Utilized Angular 5 and TypeScript to create UI components and feature specific modules.
- Integrated functional programming best practices for managing application state using Redux, NgRx and Immutable data structures.
- Wrote Front-end Unit Tests using Karma and Jasmine.

Front-End Web Developer (September 2016 – December 2016)

Touchstone Group Associates, Cincinnati, Ohio

- Utilized Touchstone's Employee Recognition API to create Volvo's internal employee recognition website.
- Developed Volvo retailer location-specific data dashboards and performance reports for individuals and groups.
- Applied several front-end web technologies such as HTML, CSS, TypeScript, JavaScript and the KendoUI framework to create the Volvo user experience.

Web Developer (October 2014–September 2016)

Gyro, Cincinnati, Ohio

- Developed the British Petroleum (BP) Driver Rewards website (mybpstation.com) utilizing the CakePHP framework.
- Integrated 3rd party BP customer data API into the BP Driver Rewards website to create gated BP Driver Reward member and registration pages.
- Integrated the VISA Offers platform into BP Driver Rewards site for BP VISA credit card sign-up.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Node.js, Typescript, React, Redux, Jest, React Testing Library, Vue.js, Vuex, Angular, Storybook.js, Electron, HTML, CSS, SCSS, GIT, Webpack, Visual Studio Code, Terminal, Figma, Photoshop

Education

B.S. Media Arts and Design

- Mt. Sierra College, Monrovia, California (2002-2007)
- Relevant coursework in design and web development

A.A. Graphic Design

- Platt College, Los Angeles, California (1997-1999)
- Relevant coursework in design, providing a strong foundation for web development